let's understand what no capping on room
rent means with a story
[Music]
there are too many people here and no
space for me to rest properly
let's ask if we can get an upgrade
[Music]
don't you think with the hospital bills
you will have to pay so much for this
room also
can you afford to stay here for five
days
yeah absolutely I have my insurance with
me right I'm covered for this accident
but bro the room I know it was crowded
but with these bills I will get a heart
attack only
yeah but my health insurance not only
covers me for my medical charges but I
don't have to pay additional room rent
even if I upgrade my room it's called No
Room rent capping it will cover you up
to the summon show
and what does that mean
oh ho no room rent capping basically
means that I can pick any hospital room
I want for my treatment and I won't be
charged additionally for the room
upgrade if my total amount is up to the
summon short
no limit on my hospital room cost my
insurance provider covers me through it
all oh okay okay so your insurance
doesn't ask you to pay a tiny percentage
either
it varies from insurer to insurer there
are policies that require a small
contribution from your side if your room
rent charges are above a certain limit
for example if the insurance provider
limits my room rent to rupees 5000 and
my actual room charges exceed this limit
then I can make a claim only for rupees
5000.
these rules are laid down by insurance
companies and are clearly specified in
the policy you choose so read carefully
before you purchase a policy
let me guess your insurance policy
offers no room rent capping right
exactly I can choose any hospital room I
want decide how my health insurance
covers me and enjoy a comfortable stay
in the hospital as long as it is up to
the sum insured
that sounds like an ideal plan to me
it is
hmm maybe you're not as slow as I
thought
[Music]
That's all folks stay tuned for more